[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to this
session on AI consumption billing in
business central. My name is Yast and
today I'm co-presenting with Ditri.
Pleasure. To start Dmitri tell me what
this is about. Yeah, it is in fact a
very fascinating topic again something
that happens for the very first time
with Business Central and the topic of
this segment is called AI consumption
billing for business central. I will
start in an interesting place. By now
you may have heard not once, not twice,
but many times about the sales order
agent. And as you probably also know,
the sales order agent is providing a ton
of value to the sales team working with
the quotes and the orders. In fact, what
you see on my screen right now is the
KPIs dashboard of an agent of the sales
order agent doing lots of great stuff.
So it did process a lot of emails,
created a lot of quotes, and many of
these quotes converted into sales
orders. So there's a lot of activity
going on and a lot of time saved by the
sales people moving along their day. But
what you might also be wondering about
is what happens with AI consumption. So
there must be a lot of AI consumed in
the back end by the sales or agent to
make its smart decisions.
Now you would be completely right
thinking about that because after a
period of time as you get a taste and
sense of the agent you will likely see a
screen looking like this. So this screen
and by the way I'm showing the copilot
and agents capabilities. We did rebrand
this page which used to be called
copilot and AI capabilities. Now it's
copilot and agent capabilities. And on
this page we list all of the co-pilot
capabilities. obviously and the sales
order agent as the first agent of
Business Central. But what's more
interesting here is a couple of
notifications that you see on the
screen. For example, that by activating
AI capabilities, you understand your
organization may be built for its use in
the future. I wanted to underscore this
statement is that at this point of time
the sales order agent is the only
capability uh which is being u built for
and we're going to explain everything
and every minor detail about that but
what you can also see is that there is
another very helpful notification here
that the AI quarter of this environment
is nearly used up so you you're getting
a feeling that you you might be
approaching a certain capacity
And at that capacity, you're being
informed and notified by the way in the
copilot pane as well. So here you can
see, hey, there's a there's a small
warning available for you that you
should probably start thinking about
what the agent is consuming. And then in
some time after that, the agent will be
stopped. And there's another message
that's going to appear that the agent
isn't processing any tasks. And you
really really need to look into what's
going on with the capacity uh spent by
the agent doing its fantastic
activities. Now, but what's happening in
this situation used? Can you shed some
light into what these terms are all
about? Yes. So to bill for copilot use
in business central um business central
will actually plug into a billing
mechanism that applies across Microsoft
products and services. Um, first of all,
Microsoft products and services will use
a common currency called the Microsoft
Copilot Studio message to measure the
usage of AI features and to build for
them. The billing of these features in
Microsoft Copilot Studio messages will
be using common meters, the generative
answers and autonomous actions. So every
time you use business central features,
they will consume a number of generative
answers or a number of autonomous
actions and that will convert into a
number of Microsoft copilot studio
messages for which you will get built.
Finally, the capacity from which these
Microsoft copilot studio messages uh are
consumed is also common across Microsoft
products and services. So there'll be
two options to purchase these. First of
all, there are the prepaid copilot
studio message packs which are monthly
subscription containing x number of
messages uh renewable every month. And
secondly, there's a pay as you go plan
where you pay for the number of copilot
studio messages you've consumed after
the month concludes. So now that we have
an idea of how uh copilot features are
built across Microsoft services, can you
tell us a little bit of what this means
for the sales order agent? Oh,
absolutely. I only pretended that I
didn't know about the topic, but thanks
a lot used for bringing up indeed very
important points in this story that it
is a common currency used by all
products. It is we use common meters
with the rest of the uh Microsoft
products and it is consuming common
capacity so to say. So what what does it
mean in terms of the sales order agent
which I just presented on the few
previous
slides. Now as you mentioned we will be
using these two specific meters
generative answers and autonomous
actions to measure the consumption of
the sales order agent and what we are
going to measure and capture are these
three specific things. So the incoming
and outgoing messages. So there is a
message coming into the sales or agent
and there is a message produced by or
generated by sales or agent in response
to that um action. There is sales quote
action when the agent does something on
for the sales quote populates the header
the lines and doing all of the updates
and there is an action on sales order uh
on the sales order converting the quote
into an order and doing the things of
that nature. So the billing pattern is
going to be very simple as Yost
explained we're going to use a
generative answer for the for any
message that the agent generates an
autonomous action for the operation on
sales quote and operation of a sales
order. So it's a very simple and
transparent billing cadence and that's
how the agent is going to be uh built.
Now a few more scenarios just just to
land that point of how it's actually
going to be tracked. Now imagine a
typical run of a sales order agent. It
receives an email asking for items and
then it creates a sales quote and it can
populate many things for that sales
quote and then in response it will
generate an email. Here's the quote with
attachment. Uh the customer reviews the
email, sends it back. So the sales or
agent will receive another one. Um
convert that quote into an order and
finally send the sales order
confirmation. So that's a very very
typical vanilla standard run and as you
can imagine it will be marked it will be
mapped to these meters generative answer
for every email message and autonomous
action for every sales quote operation
or for sales order operation. So very
very simple and here's a more advanced
scenario where the customer is now
iterating a few more times with the
sales order agent asking for some
additional specific details asking for
availability. Obviously there will be
more emails there will be more quote and
order operations and that will be that
will consume more of uh resources. So
very simple model and uh it would be
also interesting to see how you can set
it
up. Yes. So first of all we want every
business central customer to be able to
experience our co-pilot features and to
try them out. So every tenant in
business central environment comes with
a very limited preview evaluation
capacity that would allow you to set up
the sales order agent, try it out, take
it for a few runs and maybe fill a few
of your sales orders. Once that runs
out, you'll start seeing messages that
that your capacity is about to run out
and it's time to go set up your billing
policies. For that, um there's two types
of capacity as explained earlier. So,
first of all, there's the prepaid
Microsoft Copilot Studio message packs.
Um you can purchase these as a monthly
subscription and if you have any on your
tenant, this is what the agent would
consume from first. If you don't have
any prepaid capacity or you've run out
of your prepaid capacity, we'll escalate
to a pay as you go policy. So anything
beyond your prepaid capacity will be
built at the end of the month based on
how much you've consumed.
All right. By the way, Y, it sounds very
very familiar this concept of using
message packs and pay as you go. Where
where could I hear about these two
concepts? Yes, that's right. Um,
actually the power platform has been
running with this billing model for a
couple years at this point and we're
just adapting it for copilot uh
features. Right. So to have a look how
this applies to business central, we're
going into the business central admin
center, navigating to our production
environment. So here you can see I have
my business central environment in the
US currently not linked to any power
platform environment. Now as the power
platform has been using billing policies
for a few years, we are inheriting these
settings from a power platform
environment. So to use billing policies
on a business central environment is
required that you link it to a power
platform environment so that knows which
billing policies and and settings to
pick up. To do that we go into uh link
environment. We select a production
environment. So it's an environment of
the same type and in the same uh
geography. And you can see now my
environment here is linked.
So you're saying that if this
environment is already enabled for all
of these billing policies that there's
nothing else I need to be doing in this
case. That's right. If the linked power
platform environment had already set up
a billing policy in the past, the
business central environment would
automatically inherit it at this point.
Unfortunately, we can see that the
billing policy is actually not set for
this environment. So we need to go into
the power platform admin center to do
some additional setup. I can navigate
directly to the environment in the power
platform admin center from the business
center environment and you can see this
is indeed the environment here that is
linked to my business central
environment. Now to set up um a pay as
you go policy I would go into
licensing pay as you go plans and you
can see here I already have a few plans
but we'll create a new one. Um in this
case I want to build through my Azure
subscription. So I select that. I give
my billing plan a name. I pick the
subscription. I pick a resource group in
which the power platform admin center
then creates the resource against which
this would be built and I make sure that
I select copilot studio as one of the
products that is enabled for this
billing
plan. Then I select my production
environment. So this is the environment
that I just linked my environment to and
I save. And here you can see in the list
of billing plans, there's now this new
production billing plan which is um
linked to my production environment and
is enabled for copilot studio billing.
Now to confirm that I'm indeed good to
go, I navigate to copilot studio here. I
go into manage messages and I look at my
production environment and you can see
indeed here now that um this environment
has a pay as you go building plan
enabled meaning that I'm ready to go and
use copilot features on my business
central environment. Yep, that sounded
quite simple. So, so generally the
customer would need to have an Azure
subscription and then through this
experience you create a billing policy
uh associated with with an environment
and then you link that environment to
business central and that's how business
central knows where to consume these
messages from and how to report it to
the to this to that subscription. That's
quite that's quite interesting. So pay
as you go is a nice option where I don't
really know how much am I going to
spend. So this is a brilliant
opportunity for me to work with the
agent a little bit more, see how much it
consumes, measure and understand these
costs. But what if I want to have a more
rigid structure? So I want to actually
get some some prepaid capacity and
assign it to my environment. Yes. So for
prepaid capacity, there's there's two
ways of getting it. Firstly, you can
contact your partner to purchase it the
same you would a business central user
license. So it's just a monthly
subscription you purchase from a partner
and you'd have the capacity uh in that
package
available. You can also go into the
Microsoft 365 admin center first to
start a trial or to purchase directly.
So here we are in the Microsoft 365
admin center and to set up Copilot
Studio we go into
billing your
products and then add more
products. Copilot Studio falls under
business apps here. So I select that,
scroll to the bottom and I can see here
there's Microsoft copilot studio. I can
get some more
details. Um there's several plans
available. There's the message packs
that create this capacity and then
there's user licenses in case I have any
users in my tenant that want to log into
copilot studio itself and set up their
own uh
agents. For now I'll just select the
copilot studio trial. And I can see here
the checkout pane immediately pops up.
So I get one license which is an initial
trial and after that will renew into a
paid subscription. I place my order. So
now I have my confirmation that I've
started my free trial of Copilot Studio
and the message pack should be available
on my tenant to use immediately. Okay,
that was easy enough. So administrator
can get 25,000 messages to to work with
uh for their tenant and you can also get
it from your CSP partner. So that was
simple enough. But now with all of these
capacity available to my potentially
many environments, how can I try to
allocate some capacity per
environment? And uh what's also
interesting is uh I I may want to set a
certain limit that I don't want to go
beyond certain capacity using AI and
using the for example the sales order
agent or any other capability in in
another product. How would I do these
two operations? So now that we have some
prepaid capacity on this tenant, I can
go back into the Power Platform admin
center and I can see that indeed there's
now 25,000 messages available to be
allocated. Let's say for this
environment, we only want it to to cap
out at 1,000 environments. So I enter a
thousand here and I can optionally
choose um whether if that thousand is
exhausted during the subscription month.
Um this environment is allowed to draw
from any capacity in the tenant that
hasn't been used yet but that exists
beyond this thousand here or whether I
want to escalate to my uh pay as you go
billing plan. So if I want the cost of
this to be very predictable, I would
assign the the number of messages that I
want to use by this environment here and
I would disable the overages so that the
environment cannot consume more when
it's been allocated. So now that we've
set up um the capacity just as we like
it for this environment, let's go back
to the business center admin center and
have a final look. I can see that that
my production environment in the US is
indeed still linked to a power platform
environment and is now inheriting a
billing policy called production from
that environment. So this confirms that
we're good to go and the sales order
agents should start working again in our
environment. That's great news. I can't
wait to to try it much much more. All
right. So so just to to make sure that
uh I understand 100% what what you just
shared. Uh we use power platform as sort
of a billing pipeline. So it consumes
these messages available for the tenant
for the customer organization uh for all
of the products linked with that with
that tenant. And you can get it in uh
consumption pre prepaid packs, message
packs, or you can get it as pay as you
go uh depending on your needs. So if you
always consume 25,000 or more messages,
uh that this prepaid pack makes sense
for you. If you have variable
consumption, pay as you go is great.
They also work in combination. Is that
right? Mhm. So for example, once you run
out of your prepaid capacity of of
messages, then pay as you go kicks in
and then everything on top of it is
consumed through pay as you go. So
that's a very very flexible system and
you also are getting some of the uh
preview evaluation capacity just to get
a sense of what the agent is uh before
you go and and set up this um this
consumption tracking and pay as you go
and start using it. That's a great
recap. Uh that summarizes our um billing
story for the sales order agents in
business center really well. Thank you
for watching. Thank you very much.
Enjoy.